PRAMOD KUMAR

Manager-Software Solutions and IT Services(BFSI)

Summary

My current job profile is related to Sales and Business Development of enterprise software solutions, Customized software solutions, process automation based on our in-house Augment BPM (Business Process Management) framework. Second part of my profile is also related to sales of IT Services, manage services, security solutions, unified communication solutions, data centers. I also have the experience in the sales & business development of wealth management software solutions, financial planning software's, web portal management, software sales and Stock market research reports to BFSI companies. # Sales (B2B Sales, Channel Sales, Corporate Sales). # Sales Lead Generation (Domestic and International) # Customer Relationship Management (CXO Level). # Process Automation (BPM). # Social Media Marketing (LinkedIn and YouTube) # Team Building & Leadership. # Innovative Sales. # Key Account Management. Go-getter attitude with an ability to easily grasp new ideas, concepts, methods and investment techniques. Experienced in forecasting, account performance analysis, investor relations, market research, financial planning and networking.

Experience

Manager-Business Development (Software Sales & IT Services)-BFSI at Velocis Systems Pvt. Ltd. October 2013 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Velocis Systems (P) Limited is a leading player in networking, computing, messaging & collaboration, Portals, and Business Process Automation. Velocis is uniquely positioned to deliver end-to-end IT solutions beginning from cabling to collaboration to the market. Augment is the Business Process Management (BPM) Solution arm of the Velocis Group of companies. "Augment BPM", the flagship product of organization has been thoroughly tested on the ground over past few years by some of the leading organizations of India across the key industry verticals. Today augment boasts of a number of the most respected corporate as its satisfied customers in the area of Insurance, BPO, Healthcare, Automotive Manufacturing and Public Sector. Work profile (Sales & Business Development):- • Business Development of for our company Velocis Systems Pvt Ltd for this software solutions (Based on BPM-Business Process Management Technology) & IT Services, also responsible for Hunting New Business. • Account Management of Key Customers and acquire new clients (BFSI,BPO/KPO/Manufacturing etc). • Responsible for end-to-end Client Management activities in Domestic & Global corporations. • Consultingled Solution Selling for Enterprises (Banking & Financial Services, Insurance, IT/ITES/BPO, Manufacturing etc.) • Client engagement/ relation management, Consulting, Analyses Business Processes, Perform AS-IS, TO-BE and GAP Analysis and Review Requirements Management Activities. • Pre-Sales Activities, actively involved in Project Management Activities, Effort/Size Estimation of projects, Relationship Building with existing clients followed by extensive interaction with the key decision makers of New

Account. • Automated/ improved business processes across vertical domain areas - BFSI, BPO/KPO, Stock Exchanges, Manufacturing and HealthCare through BPM. • Preparing the all the documents related to project & business solutions.

Sr. Manager Sales (BFSI)-North India at ICRA Online Ltd

April 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 7 months)

Business Development (B2B Sales, Corporate Sales) & buildup a healthy relationship with CXO level persons....

2 recommendations available upon request

Manager-Marketing & Sales (BFSI) at ICRA Online Ltd

June 2010 - July 2012 (2 years 2 months)

ICRA Online is wholly owned subsidiary of ICRA Ltd., a leading Credit Rating Agency (an associate of Moody's Investors Service, Inc). ICRA Online was incorporated in Jan 1999 and has over the years established itself as an independent and credible source of authentic information and software solutions in the financial services and investment domain. Responsibilities Held: 1-Develop the market for our business in North India, focus in new segment like Media (Financial papers & web portals.), big corporate houses. 2-Total Marketing & sales of the mutual fund software's & research reports to big brokers, banks & insurance companies, brokers. 3-New business development by organizing events /seminars/ attending conferences in potential cities. 4-Preparation of marketing collaterals and strategy to effectively circulate them through e-mail marketing, website advertising, putting up stalls in summit. 5-Drive a team of relationship managers to achieve the sales target & guide to team members for enter in new segment & buildup a healthy relations with the client & generate the new business with referral model. Manage all ATL & BTL activities 6-Handling customer grievances and resolving issues related to products, services & collect the inputs/ feedback on products as other competitors in market. 7-Liaison with IT team/ Support Team to ensure quick resolution of all the customer complaints. 8-Understanding the MF research customization needs of various Mutual fund distribution houses, AMCs, Banks, Corporate and working on implementation of the same. 9-Working on product enhancement by introducing new and innovative reports in the Mutual fund Research / Financial Planning products. 10-Give the innovative & creative views for business development & enhancement in current products as per requirement and regulations change in market by the regulators.

10 recommendations available upon request

MANAGER SALES- NORTH INDIA at SAHARA ASSET MANAGEMENT COMPANY PVT LTD. NOIDA

March 2008 - June 2010 (2 years 4 months)

Sahara Asset Management Company Pvt. Ltd. Delhi/NCR, Designation: – Manager-Sales. Time Duration: 04/03/2008-15/06/2010. Work Profile:- Resource mobilization for Sahara Mutual funds through distributors across Delhi/NCR region. Marketing to the target market includes National Distributors and Independent distributors. Monitoring sales targets, budgets and producing figures and reports. Understand the needs of individuals and business customers. Deal with any complaints. Promote the company's image in the local

community. Maintain brand image and corporate policies, also being responsible for staff supervision and training. Generation of various MIS reports for effective control and co-ordination between Branch and Corporate Office. Conduct new fund offer/product presentations in the Delhi/NCR region with a view to popularize the company's pedigree. I was responsible for setting up new branches in Delhi city and heading team of 2 management trainees.

4 recommendations available upon request

PORTFOLIO MANAGER at GEOJIT BNP PARIBAS FINANCIAL SERVICES LTD

March 2007 - March 2008 (1 year 1 month)

Geojit BNP Paribas today is a leading retail financial services company in India with a growing presence in the Middle East. The company rides on its rich experience in the capital market to offer its clients a wide portfolio of savings and investment solutions. The gamut of value-added products and services offered ranges from equities and derivatives to Mutual Funds, Life & General Insurance and third party Fixed Deposits. The needs of over 495,000 clients are met via multichannel services - a countrywide network of over 500 offices, phone service, dedicated Customer Care centre and the Internet. Work Profile:- Cross sales of products to clients. Strategize financial planning to both individuals and high net worth individuals. Cross selling of all the financial products (IPO, D-Mat/Trading Accounts, Mutual Fund, insurance and PMS) but major focus on Mutual Fund products and stock market. As a financial advisor do all type of home work (Market moment, compare the funds performance, fund portfolio and switch and redemption) for advice the client for investment, buildup the portfolio and modify the portfolio. As per my experiences, knowledge and research convert loss making portfolios in to profit making portfolio. Promotion of systematic Investment Plans (SIP) for long term investment and make the change in portfolios as per market moment and client profiles and future needs. Registered and managed 150 individuals and 34 high net worth individual portfolios. Conduct seminars on market updates on a weekly basis. Generate MIS reports for effective control on client's portfolio. Make a corporate tie-up with HNPC and open more then 400 D-Mat and Trading Accounts of NHPC employees in J & K estate.

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Hindi

French (Elementary proficiency)

Courses

Independent Coursework

AMFI MUTUAL FUND ADVISOR

Skills & Expertise

CRM

New Business Development

Key Account Management

Team Building

Team Management

Market Research

Customer Service

Software sales (BFSI)

Sales- Software solutions

BPM- Business Process Management solutions

NACH

NG-RTGS

Leadership

Business Process Automation

Banking software solution

Sales Lead Generation

Business Process Re-engineering

International Sales

IT Service Management

Wealth Management software solutions

Corporate Sales Management

Mobile Phone Apps

International Sales (Mobile Apps)

Banking software solutions

Relationship Building

Payment Solutions

Managed Services

B₂B

Financial Services

Product Development

Management

Finance

Trading

Marketing Strategy

Banking

Capital Markets

Lead Generation

Investment Banking

Education

University of Lucknow

MBA, Marketing & Sales, 2003 - 2005

Activities and Societies: I am leader of Student Activity Cell and Placement Cell...

1 recommendation available upon request

CSJM University Kanpur

B.TECH., Computer Sciences & Engineering., 1998 - 2002

Interests

Management topics,Leadership and management activities,market update, technology update.making good friends for life long.

Certifications

AMFI (Mutual Fund) Advisory Module

AMFI (NSE) License 00 June 2010 to June 2015

PRAMOD KUMAR

Manager-Software Solutions and IT Services(BFSI)



17 people have recommended PRAMOD

"Pramod is pleasant, dedicated, energetic, qualified and informative, that can describe him as a person. He is extremely knowledgeable and well versed in the various nuances of marketing. His humble nature adds volumes to his personality. His humble nature adds volumes to his personality. He is going to be an asset for any organization, I can vouch for it. Hope you will remake the classic with success and happiness Wish you all the best God bless you and cheers"

— Abhijit Das, Head - Corporate Sales, Microsec Group, worked with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

"Pramod is a dedicated hardworking and energetic senior level Manager who ensures the interests of his company preced his own. A smart and talented worker who reaps profits from shear hardwork .Recommended for higher responsibilities and promotions."

— Amish Chadha, Chief Operations Officer, Bakers Dozen, was with another company when working with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

"Pramod is a very cool head professional who can remain at ease in stressful situations.and have a nice blend of both traditional and modern values of sales. He carries a rich experience of working in different components of MF industry which truely reflects from his personality. He is very active and keep himself updated & connected with the industry, his relationship handling skills are really commendable. I wish him all the success in his professional and personal life."

— Atul Sharma, Head Sales-West, ICRA Online Limited, managed PRAMOD indirectly at ICRA Online Ltd

"pramod jee is great salesman & cordinator for Execution with 100% perfection."

— Thakur Insurance &, Investment services, was PRAMOD's client

"I found Pramod as a passionate champion of mutual funds."

— **Dhirendra Kumar**, Founder and Chief Executive, Value Research, was with another company when working with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

"He is dedicated person to have in team and always there when you need him. All the best keep it up PK."

— Ranjeet Kumar Mishra, Senior Analyst, ICRA Management Cosulting Services Limited, was with another company when working with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

"Pramod is a sincere, dedicated & a professional to the core. His attitude of always giving his best to any task that he works on, is truly an asset for him"

— Rohit Singhania, Assistant Manager, ICRA Online, worked directly with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

""Pramod kumar has a versatile profile with go "getter attitude" always ready to motivate personnel with his positive attitude" Good Luck"

— sant singh, AM-HUMAN RESOURCE, SAGEM-ORGA, was with another company when working with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

"Pramod has combination of Industry Knowledge, Sales Skill & Networking ability. A person with a very Positive and an all out Go Getter Attitude. He is always honest in his approach with any kind of work coming his way. I wish him success in all his future endeavours."

— **Vikas Mishra**, *Assistant Manager*, *ICRA Online Limited*, worked directly with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

""Pramod is one of the most thoughtful, knowledgeable and professional people in ICRA Online Limited. He's got a passion for the design and development of marketing strategy of enterprises software, and is one of the "go to" people in the ICRON space for his knowledge of the market, his understanding of the issues, his original ideas and his thorough execution. I have enjoyed all of our encounters and recommend him very highly.""

— **Uday Kumar**, *Credit Analyst*, *ICRA-Credit Rating*, *New Delhi*, worked directly with PRAMOD at ICRA Online Ltd

"Pramod is a valuable resource for our company. He has worked very hard to create a niche for ICRA Online in the tough North India market. His sincere and easygoing nature are an asset which we all cherish. I wish him all the luck in his current and future endeavors."

— **Trideep Choudhary**, *Head-Research Products & Services*, *ICRA Online Limited*, managed PRAMOD indirectly at ICRA Online Ltd

"Nice dedicated guy."

— Haresh Nagpal, was PRAMOD's client

"Pramod is a very honest person in his personal and professional level both in terms in marketing he can sell anything is work with him and i know where he is going he will always work with passion. He learns things better. He know how can convert all impossible to possible."

— **Mritunjay Singh**, *Softwere Eng, ICRA Online Limited*, worked directly with PRAMOD at SAHARA ASSET MANAGEMENT COMPANY PVT LTD. NOIDA

"""Pramod is a dedicated, sincere, focussed and hardworking person. He is very innovative with lot of ideas. He possesses exempelary relationship management skills. It was a pleasure to work with him. I wish him all the very best for his future endeavours"

— Avishek Dey, Head Sales- West & South, ICRA Online Limited, worked directly with PRAMOD at SAHARA ASSET MANAGEMENT COMPANY PVT LTD. NOIDA

"Pramod is a focussed professional with excellent interpersonal skills. He believes in ever lasting relations and make sure that this bonding never fails. My best wishes to him for a successful career ahead!"

— Sandeep Singh Sengar, Area Sales Manager, Kanpur, Edelweiss Asset Management Ltd, was with another company when working with PRAMOD at Sahara Asset Management Company Pvt Ltd

"A man of few words and many works this suits to Mr. Pramod Kumar. A dynamic personality with having a innovative attitude towards his professional goal. At the same time he is very light hearted personality coupled with humanity . passionate about life and job. my best wishes for u. God Bless U"

— **Saurav Vishal**, *Branch Head/Manager- Sales and Investor Relations*, *Sahara Mutual Fund*, worked directly with PRAMOD at Sahara Asset Management Company Pvt Ltd

"Pramod is a hardworking and a sincere person and an asset to the company which he will work for. extra ordinary man with good inter personal skills."

— **Jasneet Singh Bakshi**, *Student, Indian Institute of Management, Lucknow*, studied with PRAMOD at University of Luckow

Contact PRAMOD on LinkedIn